还是没有回应，长官
Still no response, sir.
保持联络
Keep it open.
我不喜欢这种感觉
I don't like this.
第一次报告之后就再也没有消息了
Nothing since the first check-in.
史考特和苏鲁半个小时前就该联系我们了
Scott and Sulu should've contacted us half an hour ago.
可能他们没什么可报告的
They may have nothing to report.
除了登陆小队，没有发现其它生命体
Our sensors indicate no life forms except our landing party.
他们都应该清楚登陆队的规矩
Both those men are well aware of landing-party procedure.
现在应该联络我们了
They should've checked in with us by now.
船长，连接已建立
Contact established, captain.
- 杰克逊呼叫进取号 - 进取号 这里是寇克
- Jackson to Enterprise. - Enterprise. Kirk here.
- 一人等待传送，进取号 - 就一个?
- One to beam up, Enterprise. - One?
- 杰克逊，史考特和苏鲁在哪? - 我已经准备好传送了
- Jackson, where are Scott and Sulu? - I'm ready to beam up, sir.
- 杰克逊！ - 对不起，通讯不是特别清楚, 舰长
- Jackson! - I'm sorry, I can't clear it, captain.
通知传送室准备传送
Notify Transporter Room to prepare to beam up
登陆小队的一名成员
one member of the landing party.
让麦考伊医生去传送室向我报到
Then have Dr. McCoy report to me in the Transporter Room, on the double.
- 准备好了长官 - 开始传送吧
- Ready, sir. - Energise.
- 怎么了吉姆？ - 麻烦了
- What's on, Jim? - Trouble.
杰克逊，其他人呢
Jackson, where are the others?
他死了
The man is dead.
寇克舰长，你能听见吗
Captain Kirk, can you hear me?
这是一个诅咒
There is a curse on your ship.
离开这个地方
Leave this place...
否则你们都会死
... or you will all die!
宇宙，最后的边疆
Space, the final frontier.
这是星舰进取号的航程
These are the voyages of the Starship Enterprise.
它的五年任务，是去探索未知的新世界
Its five-year mission: To explore strange new worlds,
找寻新的生命与新的文明
to seek out new life and new civilisations,
勇敢的航向前人未至之境
to boldly go where no man has gone before.
【星际迷航：原初】
-=THE LAST FANTASY=-
荣誉出品
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径
-=TLF字幕组=-
翻译：德芙
校对：喜马拉雅
第二季第七集
人偶傀儡
舰长日志: 星历 3018.2
Captain's Log: Stardate 3018.2.
杰克逊死了
Crewman Jackson is dead,
没有明显的物理伤痕
and there are no apparent physical causes.
史考特和苏鲁还在下面的星球上无法联系
Mr. Scott and Mr. Sulu are still out of touch on the planet below.
我将指挥权交给了副手
Leaving Assistant Chief Engineer DeSalle in command of the Enterprise,
我要亲自去那个星球表面
I'm beaming down to the planet's surface
找到两个失踪的队员
to find my two missing crewmen...
找到杀死杰克逊的人
... and discover what killed Jackson.
奇怪，我们的数据显示没有雾
Odd. Our probe data didn't indicate fog.
没有云，也没有水
No cloud formations, no bodies of water,
表面温度没有变化
no changes in surface temperature.
在这种条件下，雾不太可能存在，船长
Under these conditions, fog is highly unlikely, captain.
根据我们的传送坐标
According to our transporter coordinates,
这就是杰克逊传送时的位置
this is the exact location from which Jackson was beamed up to the ship.
- 读数，史波克? - 还没有，等一下
- Readings, Mr. Spock? - No indications of... A moment.
有生命体的读数
Picking up life form readings:
24度方向第7类反应，距离此地137.16米处
24 degrees mark 7. Range 137.16 metres.
- 有多个生命体的读数，舰长 - 史考特和苏鲁?
- Multiple readings, captain. - Scott and Sulu?
- 寇克呼叫进取号 - 进取号
- Kirk to Enterprise. - Enterprise, Lieutenant Uhura here.
上尉现在有什么发现?
What are the ship's sensors reading now, lieutenant?
报告，先生
Report, mister.
我只收到他们三人的物理脉冲
I am only picking up physical impulses from the three of them.
根据仪器的读数
As far as the instruments can make out...
那没有其他活物了
...there is nothing else down there that's alive.
转述，上尉
Relay, lieutenant.
舰长，我们只收到你们的读数
Captain, we are only registering on you.
舰长，寇克舰长！
Captain. Captain Kirk!
上尉，你能听见我说话么?
Lieutenant, can you hear me?
不管这是什么，它越来越厚了
Whatever this stuff is, it's getting thicker.
你觉着这个跟干扰有关系吗?
Do you suppose it has anything to do with the interference?
不，肯定有办法解释这一切
No. There has to be some explanation for the fact
飞船只能识别我们
the ship's sensors can't register anything but us,
可是我们探测到了其他生命体
while we're picking up readings for multiple life forms.
- 他们还在那吗史波克? - 没有变化，舰长
- Are they still there, Spock? - No change, captain.
保持警惕
Standby alert.
听
Listen.
- 你觉得那是 - 安静
- What do you think that... - Quiet.
寇克舰长
Captain Kirk.
- 你是谁? - 回去
- Who are you? - Go back.
记住那个诅咒
Remember the curse
风要起了
Winds shall rise
雾要散了
And the fog descend
离开这，你们所有人
So leave here, all
否则将一命呜呼！
Or meet your end!
史波克，你想说啥
Spock, comment.
很差劲的诗，船长
Very bad poetry, captain.
有没有更有用的评论，史波克
A more useful comment, Mr. Spock.
我们刚才所见并不是真实的
What we've just seen is not real.
这个很有用
That's useful.
在24度方向，据此100米处
However, on Azimuth 24, at just over 100 metres,
绝对有某种生物体
there are definitely life forms.
非常诡异
Erratic, confused...
但是那边肯定有什么东西 - 我们就去那
...but definitely registering. - That's where we go.
那是非常真实的幻象，史波克
That was a pretty real illusion, Mr. Spock.
吉姆
Jim.
生命体读数就是从这来的，舰长
This is the source of the life form readings, captain.
他们就在里面某处
They're inside somewhere.
寇克呼叫进取号
Kirk to Enterprise.
进取号，请回答
Enterprise, come in.
第一波登陆队员是不是也是这样失去联系的？
Isn't that how we lost contact with the first landing party?
怎么了，史波克?
What about it, Spock?
这个建筑和通讯干扰有什么关系么?
Does this structure have anything to do with communicator interference?
我不会这样说, 船长
I would say not, captain.
没有任何证据显示和干扰有关系
There's no indication of anything that would cause such interference.
但是收不到我们飞船的信号了
And it doesn't pick up on our ship's sensors.
我们的探测器也探测不到里边生命体
Nor do our sensors register the life forms inside.
可能施加了某种力场
It could be exerting a force field of some kind
打断了我们传感器的扫描
that cuts into our sensor scan.
但是史波克的三录仪还是有效的，不是么?
Then it would affect Spock's tricorder too, wouldn't it?
会么
Would it?
我觉得会
I wonder.
三个女巫
Three witches...
看起来是一座城堡，还有黑猫
...what appears to be a castle, and a black cat.
如果不是有两个队员失联，一个队员死了
If we weren't missing two officers, and a third one dead,
我会说这是一个针对我们的“不给糖果就捣乱”恶作剧
I'd say someone was playing an elaborate trick-or-treat on us.
- “不给糖果就捣乱”，舰长? - 是啊，史波克
- Trick-or-treat, captain? - Yes, Mr. Spock.
你还不知道，有机会我解释给你听
You'd be a natural. I'll explain it to you one day.
- 我们是不是应该到处看看? - 看起来很整齐的样子
- Shall we have a look around? - That would seem to be in order.
老骨头，史波克
Bones. Spock.
他们消失了，德赛尔
They're gone, Mr. DeSalle.
船长和其他人就是探测不到了
The captain and the others. Simply stopped registering.
看看是不是故障了
Check for malfunctions.
- 我检查过了长官，一开始我就检查了 - 德赛尔
- I did, sir, as soon as it happened. - Mr. DeSalle...
史考特，他们也是这样
...that's exactly what happened to Mr. Scott and his party.
- 他们就那样消失了 - 没有人消失
- They just disappeared. - Nobody just disappears.
他们可能遇到了一个磁场
They may have encountered a magnetic field
或者其他阻碍
or some other obstruction.
契诃夫，重新校准你的传感器
Mr. Chekov, recalibrate your sensors.
- 如果你需要帮助 - 我能做到长官
- If you need help... - I can do it, sir.
我不是新手了
I'm not that green.
乌乎拉上尉，请继续努力
Lieutenant Uhura, continue your efforts
突破通讯干扰
to break through that static interference.
好的长官
Aye, aye, sir.
我知道他们就在下面我要找到他们
We know they're down there. I want them found.
- 一直往前走, 史波克? - 从读数看来是这样的
- Straight ahead, Mr. Spock? - The readings would so indicate.
灰尘，蜘蛛网
Dust, cobwebs.
还真是万圣节啊
Halloween is right.
史波克
Spock...
你没事吧? - 没事
...are you all right? - Yes.
我没有受伤，乌乎拉
I am undamaged, captain.
骨头，医生
Bones. Doc.
你说了一些“不给糖果就捣乱”的事
You were saying something about trick-or-treat.
地牢
Dungeons...
诅咒
...curses.
骨架，铁处女，这些都是地球上的啊
Skeletons and iron maidens. They're all Earth manifestations.
- 为什么? - 我不知道船长
- Why? - I do not know, captain.
但是这些事是真实存在的，他们是真的
But these things do exist. They are real.
可能是某个星球和人类进化相似？
Could this be an Earth parallel development of some sort?
这些东西跟人类进化可没有关系
None of this parallels any human development.
更像是人的
It's more like a human...
噩梦 - 如果有人知道
...nightmare. - As if someone knew
这些都是潜意识里人类害怕的
what it was that terrifies man most on an instinctive level.
鬼故事，怪物，恶魔
Ghost stories, ogres, demons.
整个
The whole...
史考特，苏鲁
Scotty, Sulu.
史考特
Scotty...
放下枪
...put down the phaser.
他们看起来被下药了, 舰长
They appear to be drugged, captain.
看他们的眼睛，基本都不眨的
Look at their eyes. They hardly blink at all.
杰克逊死前也是
Neither did Jackson, just before he collapsed.
他们俩还活着
These two are alive.
史考特，你能听见我说话吗?
Scotty, do you hear me?
苏鲁，你知道我是谁吗?
Sulu, do you know who I am?
你怎么了?
What's happened to you?
我觉得他们是来救我们的
I think they're going to release us.
停!
Stop!
你到底是谁
Whoever you are...
你已经证明了你制造幻觉的能耐
...you've proven your skill at creating illusions.
现在我想知道你为什么这么做，你对我的人做了什么
Now I want to know why, and what you've done to my men.
你们人类为何如此偏执?
Where did your race get this ridiculous predilection for resistance?
你们检查所有的西，质疑一切
You examine any object, you question everything.
就不能接受现实吗?
Is it not enough to accept what is?
只要我的人死了就不会接受
Not when one of my men is dead because of it,
- 另外两个变傻了 - 不是变傻
- and two others turned into mindless... - Not mindless.
他们俩是被控制了，寇克舰长
These two are merely controlled, Captain Kirk.
是的，我们知道你是谁
Yes, we know who you are.
你们所有人
All of you.
不是么，亲爱的?
Don't we, my precious?
你是谁?
Who are you?
为什么把我们带到这?
Why did you bring us here?
我叫克拉波
My name is Korob.
至于把你们带到这里
And as for bringing you here...
那是因为你们非要来
...it was you who quite contrarily insisted upon coming.
- 已经警告过你 - 但是为什么?
- You were warned to stay away. - But why?
到底是什么原因?
For what reason?
这些巫术到底是为了什么?
Why all the mumbo jumbo?
巫术？
Mumbo jumbo?
不, 我向你保证不是那回事, 舰长
No, I assure you it was not that, captain.
测绘显示这个星系
Mapping expeditions have charted this solar system before.
佩茹斯第七行星以前没有生命
There never have been any life forms on Pyris Vll.
这不重要，我们不是这个星球上的原住民
It is of no importance that we are not native to this planet.
有人说我待客不周，先生们
I'm told I've been an inattentive host, gentlemen.
要不要品尝一下美食恢复些体力？
You will join me for something to refresh yourselves?
- 那个猫 - 那个猫
- That cat. - That cat.
地球上有一些古老的传说，女巫和她们的宠物
There are ancient Earth legends about wizards and their familiars.
宠物？
Familiars?
撒旦把恶魔变成动物，送到女巫的身边
Demons in animal forms, sent by Satan to serve the wizard.
迷信
Superstition.
我没有编造这些传说，我只是陈述而已
I do not create the legend, captain. I merely report it.
你是与众不同的，史波克
You are the different one, Mr. Spock.
你和其他人思维方式不同
You do not think like the others.
你的逻辑中没有其他颜色
There are no colours to your patterns of logic.
只有黑和白
There's only black and white.
你看见周围这些东西
You see all this around you...
但却不相信 - 他不知道“不给糖果就捣乱”
...and yet you do not believe. - He doesn't know about trick-or-treat.
我不明白这个典故
I do not understand that reference.
没关系这不重要
Therefore it also is of no importance.
先生们，我争取做个好主人
Gentlemen, I can be most hospitable.
- 好法术 - 请坐
- Ingenious. - Do be seated.
- 我们不饿 - 但我还是坚持
- We're not hungry. - But I insist.
好吧，克拉波 你想从我们这得到什么?
All right, Korob. What do you want from us?
现在，只想你们享用美食
For the moment, merely that you eat and enjoy yourselves.
医生，请尝尝这杯酒，你会发现相当好喝
Doctor, do try the wine. You'll find it excellent.
可惜你会发现我们不怎么配合
You'll find us most uncooperative...
除非给我们一个解释
...unless you start explaining yourself.
希望我可以打破这个局面
Hopefully I can change that attitude.
- 看起来像真的 - 本来就是真的，我保证
- These look real. - They are, I assure you.
钻石，翡翠，红宝石，蓝宝石
Diamonds, rubies, emeralds, sapphires.
各种你们珍视的珠宝
All the crystalline forms you cherish above all things.
这些都是你们的了
A fortune of them for each of you,
如果你们愿意安静地离开
if you will leave here without further enquiry.
这些东西我们想造多少就能造多少
We could manufacture a ton of these on our ship for you.
- 他们对我们毫无意义 - 没有价值？
- They mean nothing to us. - Valueless?
我不懂，我读过
I don't understand. I read...
不管你读过什么，你读的不对
Whatever it is you read, you read it wrong.
时候到了我们自然会离开
As for leaving, we'll leave when we're ready.
你们真是不可预测啊
You are most unpredictable.
可能我犯了一个小错误
Perhaps I have made a small mistake.
无论如何，你已经通过测试了
Nevertheless, you have passed the tests.
- 测试? - 是的
- Tests? - Yes.
也许我们对你们的分析有误
Our analysis of you may have been, in some small way, in error...
我们警告你们离开
...but you were warned to stay away,
你们却为了解救同伴而来
and yet you came to save your comrades.
这证明了忠诚
That proves loyalty.
你们的勇敢通过了测试，你们没有被吓到
Your bravery was tested, and you did not frighten.
尽管我高估了这些东西的吸引力
And despite my failure with these bright baubles,
不过已经足够证明你们的坚定
I perceive you cannot be bribed.
从各个方面来讲,你们都是值得敬佩的
In many ways, you are quite admirable.
对了，快去吧
Quite right. Go at once, yes.
先生们，我的同僚，希尔薇娅
Gentlemen, my colleague, Sylvia.
麦考伊医生, 史波克先生
Dr. McCoy, Mr. Spock...
还有寇克船长
...and Captain Kirk.
你想知道我对你的人做了什么
You wanted to know what we did to your men.
事实上，研究人类心灵
Actually, it's a simple matter for us
对我们来说非常容易
to probe the minds of creatures like yourself.
大脑探测、催眠术？
Mind-probing. Hypnosis?
你们把自己想象成一个高等生物
You like to think of yourselves as complex creatures,
但是你们错了
but you're flawed.
有太多的方法去探测你们的大脑了
One gains admittance to your minds through many levels.
你们对自身得了解还差得远
You have too many to keep track of yourselves.
人类的大脑对我们来说就像敞开的大门
There are unguarded entrances to any human mind.
心灵感应？
Telepathy?
不全是，不对
Not entirely, no.
心灵感应无法控制
Telepathy doesn't imply control
但是我可以保证我已经完全控制了你的朋友
and I assure you that I have full control of your friends.
别动
Don't move.
看好他们
Cover them.
现在，把武器和设备还给我们
Now, I want the rest of our weapons and our equipment.
- 我想要答案 - 放下武器
- I want some answers. - Put that weapon down.
舰长, 你这么做并不明智
Captain, it seems so foolish of you to insist on demonstrations.
在你们的神话中，这叫做感应巫术
In the mythology of your race, this is called "sympathetic magic".
杰克逊，那个回到船上的队员
Jackson, the crew member who returned to the ship.
你想知道他怎么死的，我做了他的人偶
You wondered what killed him. I made an image of him.
对我来说，那就是杰克逊
In the essence of my thoughts, the image was Jackson.
当我杀死了他的人偶，就知道他已经死了
And when I killed the image and knew that it was dead...
他死了
...he died.
你不能靠想象杀死一个人
You can't think a man to death.
你的通讯器
Your communicator.
现在
Now...
联系你的飞船
...signal your ship.
别这样希尔薇娅 ，别!
Don't. Sylvia, don't!
寇克呼叫进取号，请回答
Kirk to Enterprise, come in. Come in.
- 进取号，这里是寇克舰长请回答 - 舰长
- Enterprise, I'm Captain Kirk. Come in. - Captain.
你们怎么样？你们在哪？ 其他人都好吗，长官？
Are you all right? Where are you? Are the others all right, sir?
别担心我们，你们那发生了什么？
Never mind about us. What's happening up there?
温度长官，温度一直在升高
The temperature, sir. It keeps rising.
读数
Reading, mister.
在过去的30秒内升高了60度
It's up 60 degrees in the past 30 seconds.
我们要被烤熟了
We're burning up, sir.
德赛尔
DeSalle...
把后备能源接到散热器上
...channel bypass power into your heat dissipation units.
我已经这样做了，舰长，然而没什么用
I've already done it, captain. It had no effect.
- 我们正被放在火上烤 - 好吧
- We're cooking up here. - All right.
我会处理的，寇克完毕
I'll handle it down here. Kirk out.
你赢了
You've won.
现在你可以放松了舰长，你的船很安全
You can relax now, captain. Your ship is safe.
温度基本已经恢复正常
The temperature is almost back to normal...
下降得非常快
...dropping down fast.
上尉，试着联系寇克
Lieutenant, try to raise the captain again.
进取号呼叫寇克舰长，请回答舰长
Enterprise to Captain Kirk. Come in, please.
进取号呼叫寇克舰长，请回答
Enterprise to Captain Kirk. Acknowledge.
我们找不到他们的信号，德赛尔
We've lost him again, Mr. DeSalle.
舰长，你已经看到了我们的科技
Captain, you've seen something of our science,
现在告诉我们你们的
now tell us about yours.
你似乎跟我们不在一个频道上
You seem to be singing a different tune.
我想了解你们更多，不管那是魔法还是科学
I'd rather know more about yours. You call it "magic," you call it "science".
似乎跟这两者都不一样
It seems to be unrelated to both of them.
- 你们怎么称呼它，舰长？ - 我不打算给它起名字
- What would you name it, captain? - I wouldn't attempt to name it.
但是你们的想法似乎起到了我们工具的作用
But you seem to do with your mind what we do with tools.
你们用心灵感应来改变移动物体
You alter matter, move it about by telekinesis.
- 是的我们能改变分子 - 克拉波，你说得太多了!
- Yes, we can change the molecular... - Korob, you talk too much!
你用史考特和苏鲁引诱我们来这
You kept Scott and Sulu as catspaws to lure us down here.
- 你怎么知道我们回来？ - 我们不知道
- How'd you know we'd come? - We didn't have to know.
- 他们知道 - 够了
- They knew. - Enough of this.
你会告诉我们我们想知道的
You will tell us what we want to know.
现在威胁太晚了些，你让我联系我们的船
It's too late for threats. You let me contact the ship.
你觉得一个搜索队到这会用多长时间?
How long do you think it will be before a search party arrives?
反正要些时间，舰长
Some time, captain.
相当长的时间
Quite some time.
不会有什么搜索队了，寇克舰长
There will be no search party, Captain Kirk.
舰长，你的船周围有个不能穿过的力场
An impenetrable force field around your ship, captain.
不会妨碍轨道运行，但是你的人都被困在里边了
It will not hinder orbit, but your people are prisoners within it.
听起来像一个力场，长官
It's some kind of a force field, sir.
但是和你们知道的都不一样
But not like any other I've heard of before.
不知来自何处
It's not coming from anywhere...
只是在我们周围
...it's simply all around us.
我建议你最好合作，舰长
I would advise you to cooperate, captain.
强行从你们大脑里抽取我们需要的信息并不难
Forcible extraction of the information we wish from you is not complicated,
但这很疼，并且很可能会有生命危险
but it is extremely painful. And it has a certain
我们没什么好谈的
- draining effect. - We have nothing to discuss.
带他们去牢房待着
Take them to their cell.
等等
Wait.
医生留下
The doctor will stay.
你是下一个，舰长，早晚都一样
Your turn will be next, captain. It makes little difference.
带他们离开
Take them out of here.
波长分析，契诃夫?
Wavelength analysis, Mr. Chekov?
无法分析，长官
It will not analyse, sir.
好吧
All right.
但是力场在那，是真实存在的
But it's there, and it's real.
如果是真实存在的，就应该被探测到
If it's real, it can be affected.
操控室，准备将所有能量都转移到外壁上
Engineering, standby to divert all power systems to the outer hull.
准备将脉冲引擎升至最大功率
Prepare impulse engines for generation of maximum heat
准备就绪
directed as ordered.
可能我们拿它没办法
Maybe we can't break it,
但是我们会努力在上面撞出个坑
but I'll bet you credits to navy beans we can put a dent in it.
用了多长时间了?
How long has it been?
- 22分钟17秒 - 谢谢
- 22 minutes,17 seconds. - Thanks.
我在想他们会对医生做什么
I wonder what they're doing to Doc.
我们一会就知道了
I'm sure we'll find out shortly.
吉姆
Jim...
我们看到的这些东西
...all these things that we've seen...
他们和地球人太像了
...to an Earthman like yourself they must seem quite familiar.
相似，令人惊讶
Familiar. Startling...
没有道理 - 对极了
...not rational. - Precisely.
我想和你谈谈关于种族潜意识的心理学
I refer you to the psychological theory of the racial subconscious.
- 各种神话，符号 - 你的意思是鬼、巫师?
- The universal myths, symbols. - Ghosts, witches, you mean?
还有地牢，城堡和黑猫
And dungeons, and castles, and black cats.
他们都属于模糊的意识世界
They all belong to the twilight world of consciousness.
- 他们试图探测我们的意识 - 但是他们失败了
- They tried to tap our conscious mind. - And they missed.
他们只是探测到了我们的潜意识
They reach basically only the subconscious.
你对那些测试的反应
Korob seemed quite puzzled...
似乎弄得克拉波心烦意乱
...by your reaction to the environment he had provided.
他期望我反应的像正常一样
He expected me to react as though it were all normal.
他承认他们不是这个星球的原住民
He admitted they weren't native to this planet.
而且属于和我们不同的科学体系
And not to have a knowledge of our scientific methods
和我们在银河系见过的其他生命都不一样
is most unlikely, for any life form we've met in this galaxy.
他们叫我们生物
They refer to us as "creatures"...
就好像我们是某种未知生物
as though we were some species they were unfamiliar with.
如果我们是生物
If we're creatures...
你猜他们到底是什么？
I wonder what they're really like?
很显然，对我们绝对是
Evidently something...
完全是外星人
...totally alien in all respect.
同意，完全是外星人
Agreed. Totally alien.
我不喜欢有敌意的陌生人
I don't like hostile strangers
还对我们的星系和世界有着强烈的兴趣
showing such an acute interest in our galaxy,
完全不像友善的访客
our world, Spock. Not at all like friendly visitors.
我们必须阻止他们，毫不留情
We're going to have to stop them. Cold.
但是同时
But at the moment...
现在我也没什么办法了
I too, am at a loss at this time to suggest a course of action.
老骨头
Bones.
医生
Doc.
你忘了我们来这是为了什么
You forget what we were sent here for.
我什么也没忘，我不是宠物，克拉波，不像你
I forget nothing. I'm not a puppet, Korob, like you.
- 你是个背叛者！ - 你是个笨蛋！
- You're a traitor! - You are a fool!
看看这些我们所没有的
We have nothing like this.
我喜欢极了
And I like it.
触摸，感受，理解享受的含义
To touch, to feel, to understand the idea of luxury.
我喜欢这样
I like it...
而且我不愿意失去它
...and I don't intend to leave it.
- 我们得对上头负责任 - 他们根本不懂什么叫知觉
- We have a duty to the Old Ones. - What do they know of sensations!
- 这是一个新世界 - 你太残酷了
- This is a new world. - You're cruel.
那样折磨我们的样品
You torture our specimens.
那也是一种新鲜的体验，我觉得非常刺激
And that too, is a new sensation. I find it stimulating.
你错了！
You're wrong!
你正在抛弃你所赖以生存的一切
You're discarding everything we live by.
这是我自己的决定，你是个懦夫，克拉波
I live by my own decisions. You're a weak fool, Korob.
- 我有这个能力 - 但是你却害怕使用它
- I have the power. - But you're afraid to use it.
不要逼我
Don't threaten me.
我可以制服你
I can squash you,
这种感觉很有趣
and that would be an interesting sensation, yes.
我发现我喜欢上了这些新感觉
I find I like these new sensations.
不要试图逼我
Don't try to push me.
舰长
Captain...
我们该谈谈了
...it's time for our talk.
克拉波，给我们一点空间带着这些人跟你走
Korob, leave us alone and take these men with you.
这还没完，希尔薇娅
This is not ended, Sylvia.
但是很快就完了，老人家
But it may end soon, old man.
现在谈吧？
What now?
是不是你挥挥魔法棒就能摧毁我的意志？
Do you wave your magic wand and destroy my mind too?
这不是对大脑的真实伤害，舰长
There's no real damage to the mind, Captain.
- 只是输入知识和意愿 - 这还不算伤害？
- Simply a drain of knowledge and will. - You don't call that damage?
算吗？
Why should I?
你要知道
You'd know...
如果你有同情心的话
...if you had compassion.
一个女人应该有同情心
A woman should have compassion.
- 但是我忘记了你不是女人 - 你错了舰长
- But I forget you're not a woman. - But you're mistaken, Captain.
我现在是个女人了
I am a woman now.
你我都知道我来自一个没有知觉的世界
I come from a world without sensation as you and I now know it.
真令人兴奋，我还需要更多
It excites me. I want more.
看起来你很需要我们，为什么?
You seem to need us. Why?
因为你有我们缺少的知识
Because you have knowledge which I lack.
如果我们的能力可以放在一起
But were our abilities put together...
跟我说说力量，舰长
Tell me about power, captain.
它感觉起来是什么样的？
How does it feel?
克拉波呢？
What about Korob?
他是个傻瓜，没有他也行
He is a fool. I'll do without him.
但是你
But you...
为什么我觉得你与众不同？
...why do I find you different?
为什么我觉得很难对付你？
Why would it be so difficult to dispose of you?
要不你直接到我大脑里找找答案
Why don't you simply probe my mind and get what you want?
不行那可不行，你不可以
No. Not that, not for you.
我想要的是
What I want is...
是联合起来
...is a joining.
你我心意相合，心甘情愿
My mind to yours, willingly.
想想你会知道的那些秘密 想想你会掌握的那些能力
Think of the secrets you could learn, think of the power that would be yours.
只要你能想到，我都能给你
Anything you can imagine, I can give you.
你可真能说
You're very persuasive.
如果我这么做了会发生什么？
What happens if I go along?
那我们将拥有一切
Then everything would be ours together.
我从没想过联合，太刺激了
I've never conceived of the idea of togetherness before. It excites me.
你让我感到兴奋，为什么？
You excite me. Why?
就跟你让我兴奋的原因一样
For the same reasons you excite me.
你真是个美丽的女人
You're a very beautiful woman.
你觉得我很美丽？
You find me beautiful.
我可以变成各种样子
But I can be many women.
喜欢吗
You like what you see?
还是你喜欢我以前的样子？
Or do you prefer me as I was?
你让我左右为难
You have a knack for giving me difficult choices.
能不能让我看看你原来的样子？
You have nothing like that where you come from?
不行
Nothing.
你们什么时候到这里的
Your people, when they come here...
没有变形器他们就像风中的羽毛
They're like feathers in the wind, without the transmuter.
- 变形器？ - 源泉
- The transmuter? - The source.
你会明白的，我以后教给你
You will learn. I will teach you later.
这是一个装置，就像你们用的工具
Then it's a device. You do use tools.
它只能给出形式，你要教我内容
It gives only form. You are teaching me substance.
你真是顽固，可你已经回不去了
You haven't changed your mind. You won't return home.
我的家就在这，和你在一起
My home is here with you.
有数十亿的感知世界任你选
A billion worlds of sensation to pick and choose.
你在利用我
You are using me!
你把我抱在怀里，心中却没有燃起一丝火花！
You hold me in your arms, and there is no fire in your mind!
你在骗我
You're trying to deceive me.
就像书里写的那样！
It's here, like words on a page!
- 你在利用我 - 为什么不呢？
- You were using me. - Why not?
你一直在利用我和我的队员
You've been using me and my crew.
你们会被消灭
You will be swept away.
你，你的人，你的船
You, your men, your ship,
你的世界！
your worlds!
- 我没有看到任何改变 - 就在这，上尉
- I don't see any change. - It's there, lieutenant.
这是我们建立的电场，德赛尔
It was that electrical field we set up, Mr. DeSalle.
那个你想要的坑
That dent you wanted.
还不够, 但是是个好的开始
It's not much, but it is a start.
继续，契诃夫
Keep it up, Mr. Chekov.
输出一，二，三号反应堆的能量
Channel the entire output of reactors
都接到中继站上
one, two and three, into the relay stations.
不管它是什么，它都开始变弱了
Whatever it is, it's starting to weaken.
我刚刚将你们的船的模型移出了晶体
I have released the model of your ship from the crystal.
他们现在应该自由了
Although they would have freed themselves soon.
很难在这么短的时间内控制这么多的东西
It is difficult to control so many things in so little time.
给
Here...
你们必须在她发现武器消失前离开
...you must go before she finds the weapon is missing.
- 我不会只顾自己逃跑 - 他们不再是你的人了
- I'm not leaving without my men. - They're not your men anymore.
他们是希尔薇娅的人，我不再控制他们
They belong to Sylvia. I can no longer control them...
还有她
...or her.
她疯了
She's irrational.
在收集你们的感觉和精力的过程中
It's the strain of adopting to your form.
变得贪心起来
The insatiable desire for sensation and experience.
她很危险，其实没有这个必要
She's a great danger. And it was not necessary.
我们本来会和平的进入你们星系
We could have entered your galaxy in peace.
- 你们坐飞船来? - 我们通过变形器
- You came in a ship? - We used a transmuter.
变形器，是的她提过
Transmuter. Yes, she mentioned that.
没时间解释了，她要把我们全部摧毁
There's no time to explain now. She means to destroy us all.
可能还有一线生机，快点
There may still be a chance. Quickly.
来
Come.
真奇妙
Fascinating.
- 为什么是猫？ - 种族的记忆
- Why a cat? - Racial memories.
猫是最残忍的
The cat is the most ruthless, most terrifying of animals.
比远古的剑齿虎都要残忍
As far back as the sabre-toothed tiger.
我想我能阻止她
I think I can stop her.
你最好让我们来
You'd better let us.
相位枪没能量了，一定是被她抽走了
It's out of energy. She must have drained it.
我们随时可能会遇到史考特和苏鲁
We could've jumped Scott and Sulu any time, if we'd known.
- 逃不掉的 - 交给我吧
- No way out. - That's my problem.
我和她是同类
She's one of my kind.
快来
Come quickly.
- 你觉得可行? - 准备好了告诉我，舰长
- You think you can make it? - Ready when you are, captain.
准备好了
Get ready.
不！
No!
快回来！
Get back!
回来回来！
Get back! Get back!
- 克拉波，这门要停不住了 - 快回来！
- Korob, the door won't last. - Get back!
快走！
Go. Go!
快点，舰长
Quickly, captain.
克拉波似乎觉得这个十分重要
Korob seemed to think this was important.
他说过一些关于变形器的事
He said something about a transmuter.
舰长，如果可以请快点
Captain, a bit more alacrity, if you please.
舰长
Captain.
医生
Doc.
吉姆！
Jim!
- 至少我们找到他们了 - 真是好幸运啊，舰长
- At least we found them. - Fortuitous, captain.
现在人都齐了？
And now that we have them all together?
可实际情况不容乐观，舰长
A most unpleasant situation, captain.
如果你的还有能量
If only your phaser had some power.
可能我们真有呢
Maybe we do.
希尔薇娅
Sylvia...
变形器在我手上，这是我的了
...I have the transmuter. It's mine now.
你很聪明，舰长，比我想的还要聪明
You're very clever, captain. More so than I'd imagined.
聪明，机智
Clever, resourceful,
- 还很帅 - 别让她碰到你的魔杖，舰长
- and handsome. - Don't let her touch the wand, captain.
吉姆！
Jim!
- 你还没玩够这些游戏吗? - 我从来不玩游戏，把它给我
- Don't you get tired of these games? - I've never played games. Give it to me.
以前我还不确定，不过现在
I wasn't sure before, but I am now.
这就是你的能量源泉，变形器
This is the source of your power, the transmuter.
不，不是源泉
No, not the source.
它基本上是个放大器，思想是源泉
It's merely an amplifier, a director. The mind is the source.
我的思想很简单，但是你的思想是关键
Mine is simple. But yours has the key.
- 但是你不知道怎么用它 - 我学得很快
- But you don't know how to use it. - I catch on quickly.
现在还不晚，寇克舰长，跟我合作吧
It's not too late, Captain James Kirk. Come with me.
- 我教你，你教我 - 为什么？你们的人是不是一无所有
- I'll teach you, you'll teach me. - Why? Do your people
所以才这么需要我们？
have nothing of their own? Is that why you need us?
我们需要你的梦想，你的野心 有了它们我就可以实现
We need your dreams, your ambition. With them I can build.
- 把变形器给我 - 不
- Give me the transmuter. - No.
你个白痴！
You fool!
你知道你放弃了什么吗？
Don't you know what you're giving up?
所有你们人类渴望的东西
Everything that your species finds desirable.
看着我！我是一个女人，完完全全的女人！
Look at me! I am a woman. I am all women!
我不知道你是什么，但是你不是个女人
I don't know what you are, but you're not a woman.
你折磨我的人，拿走他们的意识
You've tortured my men and taken their minds from them.
你索取爱却以痛苦回报
You ask for love and return pain instead.
克拉波错了，我没有摧毁你们的武器
Korob was wrong. I didn't destroy all your weapons.
把变形器给我
Give me the transmuter.
把它给我！
Give it to me!
- 怎么了，吉姆？ - 这可要好好解释了，老骨头
- What happened, Jim? - That'll take some explaining, Bones.
- 全都不见了 - 也不是都不见了
- Everything's vanished. - Not everything.
这是克拉波和希尔薇娅本来的样子
Korob and Sylvia as they really are.
他们之前的样子都是幻象 就像城堡和其他东西
Their forms were an illusion, just like the castle and everything else.
没有了能量他们就显原形了
Only the power-pack gave them reality.
有趣，和我们星系完全不同的生命体
Fascinating. A life form totally alien to our galaxy.
如果我们可以保存研究这些
If we could preserve and study this.
太迟了
Too late.
所有的这些，都只是幻象
All of this, just an illusion.
不全是幻想
No illusion.
杰克逊死了
Jackson is dead.
寇克呼叫进取号，请回答
Kirk to Enterprise. Come in.
- 请准备, 舰长 - 倒数五秒钟开始传送
- Standing by, captain. - Five to beam up.
TLF字幕组欢迎你，欢迎有志之士加入
TLF微博http://weibo.com/tlfsubs/
TLF中文字幕站http://tlfsubs.eastgame.org/